人人影视
YYeTs.com
原创翻译  双语字幕
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新
请登陆www.YYeTs.com
你被监视着
You are being watched.
■
・ 翻译  somehacker
・ 翻译  惠子
■
・ 翻译  油炸电风扇
政府有一套秘密系统
The government has a secret system--
■
・ 翻译  卫老哥
・ 翻译  王小麦
一台每时每刻都在监控你的机器
a machine that spies on you every hour of every day.
■
翻  面条打包子
译  幸田实果子
我设计这台机器是为了侦测恐怖行动
I designed the machine to detect acts of terror
■
・ 校对  阿好
但它却看到了一切
but it sees everything--
■
压制  灰灰是菇凉
牵涉普通人的暴力罪行
violent crimes involving ordinary people.
阿包  兜兜爹  凭陵新月  阿包  兜兜爹  凭陵新月  阿包  兜兜爹  凭陵新月  阿包  兜兜爹  凭陵新月
■
时间轴
政府认为这些人无关紧要
The government considered these people irrelevant.
我们不
We don't.
受当局追捕  我们只能秘密活动
Hunted by the authorities, we work in secret.
你永远找不到我们
You'll never find us.
特效
灰灰
但无论是受害人还是行凶者
But victim or perpetrator,
总监
阿好
只要你的号码被列出来  我们就会找到你
if your number's up, we'll find you.
疑犯追踪
第三季 第七集
■
监控分析
获取手机
号码确认
主体
铁尼  雷蒙德
你肯定想不到那瑞典人干嘛去了
You won't believe what the Swede has been doing--
铁尼  雷蒙德
凶案组警探
进行心理治疗
going to the therapy.
那治疗师知道多少
How much does the therapist know?
这样舒适吗
Are you resting comfortably?
是的  但我得承认
Yes. But I should tell you that,
我不太相信催眠
I don't really believe in hypnotism.
催眠是出于自由意志
The act of hypnosis is freewill.
要开始进行  你的思维必须敞开
For me to proceed, your mind must grant the permission.
第一次会有疗效吗
Will it work on me the first time?
我大多数客户是在三五次治疗后才有效果
Most of my clients experience results in three to five sessions.
我们得一步步解决你的焦虑和偏执
So we'll work on your anxiety and paranoia gradually.
冉先生
See, Mr. Wren,
其实催眠不过是意象的放松
hypnosis is merely relaxation combined with imagery.
这种经历就类似于你堕入睡眠
You experience it every night as you drift asleep,
复制手机
海登・普赖斯
未完成
强制配对失败
沉浸书中  或者恍惚错过高速公路的出口
focus on a book, or miss your exit on the F.D.R.
-准备好了吗  -我想是的
- Ready? - I think so, yes.
那开始吧
Then let's begin.
请拿起旁边的平板电脑
Please pick up the tablet beside you,
选一张最能代表你情绪的图像
and choose an image that speaks to your emotion.
这张
This one.
闭上你的眼睛
I want you to close your eyes
在脑中想象那幅图像
and form a mental picture of that image.
想象那些鸟儿  那片旷野
Picture the birds, the field.
然后一只接着一只
Then one by one,
想象它们一一飞走
picture them as they fly away.
专心于呼吸
Focus on your breathing.
一只鸟飞走了
One bird departs.
随着鸟一只只飞走  你越来越放松
And as each one goes, your relaxation increases
越来越平静  越来越安宁
and you continue to feel calmer and more at rest.
两百块一小时  芬奇
For 200 bucks an hour, Finch,
你可别光打个巨贵的盹儿
I hope you get more than an expensive nap.
我要带你回到你这一生中
I want to take you back to a place in your life
最安全最舒适的地方
where you were safe and comfortable.
能想想那个地方吗  冉先生
Can you think of that place, Mr. Wren?
我童年时的卧室
My childhood bedroom.
现在  想想让你感觉安全的一切
Now, I want you to think of all the ways it made you feel safe.
想象得清楚一点
Picture it clear as day.
墙壁是什么颜色的
What color were the walls?
海登・普赖斯
Hayden Price--
上东区的认证催眠治疗师
certified hypnotherapist to the Upper East Side.
做生日派对表演吗
Does he do birthday parties?
不是那种催眠  里瑟先生
It's not that kind of hypnotism, Mr. Reese.
他主要是服务于豪商巨贾和社会名流
He caters to wealthy businessmen and socialites.
愤怒管理  烟瘾戒断  如此之类
Anger management, smoking cessation, that sort of thing.
也许你还不知道
Or so you might think, if you didn't know
他的办公室是短期租借的
that the office was rented on a short-term lease,
而他的认证资格
and that his certification
我找不到其颁发机构
doesn't come from any association I can find.
治疗期间
During the therapy,
我想明白了海登问那些问题的含义
I became attuned to the kind of questions that Hayden was asking.
最喜欢的颜色  蓝色
A color that's favorable to you--blue.
童年宠物的名字  哨兵
The name of a childhood pet--Scout.
他在钓鱼
He was fishing--
要安全问题的答案
getting answers to your security questions.
我的银行账户忽然开始
My bank account was suddenly signed up
自动循环捐款给一家非营利组织
for a recurring automatic donation to a nonprofit
名叫"美国癌症基金"
called "The American Cancer Coalition Fund."
我赌海登的名字肯定在那家非营利组织中
I'd be willing the wager that Hayden's name is on that nonprofit.
所以  除非他的第二职业是当圣人
So, unless he's moonlighting as a Samaritan,
我看这位是骗子
I'd say we're dealing with a con artist
极聪明的贼
and a very clever thief.
那你干嘛要合作啊  芬奇
So why'd you even play along, Finch?
我只是告诉海登他想听到的
I told Hayden what he wanted to hear.
我童年根本没宠物
I didn't even have a pet as a child.
但我黑他的手机时
But when I went to bluejack his phone,
被墙在外了
it was blocked.
已经有人黑进去了
Someone had already jacked it,
也许是有人找他报仇了
perhaps someone who's out to get him.
看来最好是从他的客户着手
And his clients would be the best place to start.
我联系肖来帮忙
I'll contact Shaw for back-up,
不过我得先去看看我们的客人
but first I need to look in on our houseguest.
格罗夫斯女士  里瑟先生一如既往等在楼上
As before, Ms. Groves, Mr. Reese is upstairs
守着数目夸张的武器
with an unhealthy number of firearms.
请不要试图逃走
Please don't try to run.
说真的  哈罗德  就这么锁着我吗
Honestly, Harold, locking me up?
我承认居住条件不太理想
I admit that the accommodations are not ideal.
但监禁你  对你有好处
But your confinement is for your own good.
哈罗德  是你的机器打电话给我的
Harold, your machine called me.
此事我还未能理出头绪
An event that I haven't fully reasoned out.
但你喜怒无常  不惜伤人
But your unpredictability, your willingness to hurt others
依旧危险
make you as dangerous as ever.
你无法抗拒未来
You can't fight the future.
我会带新书给你
I'll bring you some new books.
我明白
I get it.
你奇怪为何
You wonder why
它不跟你说  却跟我说
it won't talk to you like it talks to me.
别嫉妒  哈罗德
Don't be jealous, Harold.
妈咪对我们俩都爱
Mom still loves us both.
既然无法黑入海登手机
When bluejacking Hayden didn't work,
我就送了一篮点心聊表谢意
I sent him a basket of pastries as a thank you.
当然带监听器
Bugged, of course.
我太生她的气了  简直想杀了她
I'm just so angry with her, I could kill her.
随着你越来越平静  那些感觉会消退
And those feelings will dissipate as you feel calmer,
赛克斯先生
Mr. Sykes.
说说你母亲
Tell me about your mother.
说出她的名字  大声点
Speak her name, out loud--
她的全名
her full name.
玛丽
Mary.
-玛丽・夏克福德・赛克斯  -很好
- Mary Shackford Sykes. - Very good.
允许访问
很好的开始
That's a start.
看起来治疗起作用了  斯凡
It seems therapy has helped, Sven.
我好几个月没这么安稳地睡过觉了
I haven't been able to sleep this well in months.
你仍认为周围充满假货吗
And do you still believe you're surrounded by phonies?
很悲哀  是的
Sadly, yes.
但是多亏你  我可以忘掉过去
But thanks to you, I'm able to push past,
重新用心经营我的古董生意
to rediscover the quality and craft of my antique business,
寻找我工作的意义
search for the meaning in my work.
看来海登这治疗师也不太烂
Sounds like Hayden isn't a half-bad therapist after all.
今天病人很多吗
A lot of patients today?
有怪人吗
Anybody weird?
一堆的母亲情结
Wall-to-wally mommy issues.
导致人产生烟瘾
Enough to make a man want to smoke.
或睡眠不足
Or under-sleep
或暴饮暴食  或
or over-eat or--
或
Or?
那女孩是谁  芬奇
Who's the girl, Finch?
她叫娜塔莉・波尔
Her name is Natalie Boal.
在下城区的一家美术馆工作
She works at an art gallery downtown.
她从一年前开始接受海登的治疗
She started coming to Hayden for therapy a little over a year ago.
现在可不只是治疗了
It's more than therapy now.
瞧瞧
Look at that.
他不是在工作  他爱上她了
He isn't working her, he's in love.
就她看他的那眼神
And if she's making those eyes at him,
她肯定不知道他那些犯罪勾当
I bet she doesn't know about his criminal side.
有一天  不再有病人
Someday, no more patients.
不再有精神病
No more psychoses.
不再有傲慢的艺术品买家
No more snooty art buyers.
只有你我
Just you and me.
我们去机场
We just go to the airport...
飞去世界的某个角落
Jet off to some corner of the world.
是啊
Right.
钱在哪里来着
With what money, again?
钱的问题交给我
Let me worry about that.
等我赚够
And when I get enough,
就只要你  我  天堂
it's just you and me and paradise.
海登离开了  芬奇
Hayden's on the move, Finch.
根据他的日程计划
According to his schedule,
他今天没有预约了
he doesn't have any more appointments today.
那他这是急着去哪儿
So where is he going so fast?
-给  -谢谢
- There you go. - Thank you.
事情都顺利吗
So, is everything in order?
放松
Relax.
没什么好担心的
There's nothing to worry over.
汇率对你有利
The exchange rates are in your favor.
我在S&L公司从出纳做起的
I started as a teller at that S&L, you know?
干了十五年
15 years I put in,
现在居然给我降薪
and then they tell me I need to take a pay cut.
所以我决定给自己涨薪
So I decided they owed me a pay raise.
这是我的五万美元  罗素先生
Here's my $50,000, Mr. Russell.
你的呢
Where's yours?
很好  开始进行吧
Outstanding. Let's proceed.
我一定要崩了这小子
I'm so gonna shoot this punk.
事情不太对
Something's not right.
我们在这里见你的联络人吗
We're meeting your contact here?
这里安静  远离那些想偷钱的贼
It's quiet up here, and far from nosy thieves looking for cash.
不  这里唯一的贼是你
No. The only thief here is you.
戴克警探  纽约警局  欺诈调查科
Detective Decker, NYPD Fraud Investigation.
举起手来  白痴
Hands up, sucker.
白痴
Sucker?
我猜猜他怎么诓你的  伙计
I can only guess what he got you for, pal.
他跟你扯了那套汇率鬼话
He feed you that line of crap about the exchange rates?
你  把公文包慢慢递过来
And you, pass me that briefcase very slowly.
休想
Not today.
天啊
Oh, God.
里瑟先生  肖女士
Mr. Reese, Ms. Shaw,
你们为什么不干预
Why aren't you intervening?
等着瞧啊
Wait for it.
他走了吗
Is he gone?
夹着尾巴跑了
With his tail between his legs.
我们真骗了那小子两万美元
We really hooked that fish for 20 Gs?
当然
Sure did.
两万  不是五万吗
20? I thought it was 50.
这是你那一半
Here's your half.
咱们快点儿走吧
Now let's get the hell out of here
别等叫来真警察
before somebody calls the real cops.
海登还有什么人不骗的吗
Who isn't Hayden ripping off?
这小子有两手
This guy's good.
一直看你搅咖啡倒也可以
I can watch you nursing that coffee for just so long.
要知道  我给你电话是想问你近况  乔丝
You should know I called, to check in on you, Joss.
开开罚单  抓抓小偷
Parking tickets and purse snatchers
跟我以前的活比起来没什么挑战性  奎恩先生
aren't exactly a challenge after my old job, Mr. Quinn.
叫我阿伦佐就好
Alonzo, please.
我们上次见面的时候  你说
The last time we met, you said
怀疑我教子的谋杀案有问题
you had suspicions about my godson's murder.
我试着跟进几条线索
I tried working a few leads,
但是  卡尔的部门档案被封了
but Cal's department file was sealed.
有种可能是
There is a chance here
跟HR组织有关系
that the organization HR could be involved.
HR
HR?
我还以为HR已经解体了
I thought HR was disbanded.
联调局只是抓了些小喽
The Feds just scattered the roaches.
很难把他们一网打尽
It's sometimes hard to get 'em all.
我也许可以让市长介入
Maybe I can get the mayor involved,
叫警察厅总部配合下你
open doors for you at 1 PP.
我不想让你陷入那种境地
I wouldn't wanna put you in that kind of position,
奎恩先生
Mr. Quinn.
我还是自己来吧
I'll take my chances on this one solo.
好吧
All right.
抱歉  该我轮班了
I'm sorry, my shift is starting,
我还得去接个菜鸟搭档
and I have a rookie partner to pick up.
给你配了个菜鸟啊
Saddled you with a rookie, huh?
外加罚单和小偷
Goes with the parking tickets and purse snatchers.
谢谢你的咖啡
Thanks for the coffee.
来自西蒙斯
她会是个麻烦吗
虽然海登违法犯罪  四处行骗
Despite Hayden's criminality and his malfeasant theatrics,
我还是觉得应该是
I still think it's more likely
有人想要害他  而非相反
that someone is out to get him than the other way around.
黑进他手机的人
Someone who bluejacked his phone.
也许他的某位客户识破骗局了
Maybe one of his clients is on to his scam.
倒不管海登骗过多少人
Hayden may have conned any number of people,
只要其中有一位上当者
and all it takes is one easy mark
跟混混或黑帮有关就够了
with ties to a gang or organized crime,
所以我们不能浪费时间
so we don't have a moment to waste.
请你和肖女士去拜访
If you and Ms. Shaw could visit
他几位脾气暴躁的客户
some of his more irascible clients,
我路上发给你们姓名和地址
I'll text you their names and addresses on my way.
-你去哪儿  -去接着治疗
- On your way to where? - Back to therapy.
冉先生  听到我的响指
Mr. Wren, when I snap my fingers,
你将完全走出休眠状态
you will come totally out of your resting state
感受到交谈后的振作和放松
feeling refreshed and relieved after our conversation.
这次进行得如何
So how did it go this time?
很好
Quite well.
进展良好  冉先生
You're making very solid progress, Mr. Wren.
但可惜  我们今天的治疗时间到了
But sadly, our time is up for the day.
你确实擅长于此  普赖斯先生
You really are very good at this, Mr. Price.
很高兴我被推荐给你
I'm so glad that I was referred to you.
你在哪里接受的训练
Where did you receive your training?
巴林杰催眠学院
The Barringer Hypnosis Institute.
-在纽约这儿吗  -在加州塔善那
- Here in New York? - Of Tarzana, California.
好像没听说过
I don't believe I know it.
你是怎么到这儿的
What brought you all the way out here?
通常我才是提问的人  冉先生
You know, I'm usually the one asking the questions, Mr. Wren.
你说是被谁推荐给我的来着
Who was it you said referred you to me again?
瞧  你说得对
Look at that. You're right.
我们今天的治疗时间到了
Our time is up for the day.
小子  过来
Kid, come here.
是  长官
Yes, sir.
铁尼说你一直盯着卡特
Terney says you've been keeping an eye on Carter.
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
愿意更进一步  干点实事儿吗
Willing to step up, get your hands dirty?
什么意思
What does that mean?
我们一个洗钱的人出了点麻烦
We're having trouble with a money launderer.
把事儿办砸了
Guy messed up big.
但我们需要他再干一件活儿
But we need him to finish one more job.
然后你除掉他  挖个洞
Then you pull his card, dig a hole.
埋了他
Rest in peace.
那是谁  那目标
Who's the guy? The target?
过来  小子
Come on, kid.
我们去实地考察
We're taking a field trip.
现在拍卖这个足球
And we're selling the soccer ball.
30万美元起拍
And I have your bid at $300,000.
31万  这边31万
Now 310,000. 310,000 right here.
32万
320,000.
我们来这里干什么
What are we doing here?
就是他
That's your guy.
他叫斯凡
His name is Sven.
他是城区的古董商
He's an antique dealer down in the Village.
我们叫他"瑞典人"
We call him "the Swede."
-你什么情况  -你先
- So, what's your story? - You first.
我在查HR
I'm following an HR lead.
他们要除掉一名瑞典人古董商
They wanna whack a Swedish antique dealer
因为他搞砸了他们的洗钱活动
for screwing up their money laundering.
有意思
That's funny.
我在跟一名骗子治疗师
I'm on a con man therapist
他恰好有个病人是瑞典古董商
who happens to have a Swedish antique dealer as a patient.
我就装明白吧
I'll pretend that makes sense.
我觉得这骗子可能想搞
I think my con man might be after
那瑞典人和他洗的钱
your Swede and his laundered money.
如果是HR的钱
If that's HR's money,
那骗子可要倒大霉了
your con man is in for a world of hurt.
我盯紧那骗子  不让他出事儿
I'll stick with the con man, keep him out of trouble.
我盯紧那古董商  看有什么线索
I'll stick with the antique dealer, see where he leads.
一次
We are going once.
两次
We are going twice.
成交  1911年何那斯・华格纳棒球卡
Fair warning on this 1911 Honus Wagner baseball card,
正式拍出
is sold, right here.
103号  90万美元
Number 103 for $900,000.
明天  你就送他上路
Tomorrow, you're gonna punch that guy's ticket.
意想不到啊
What do you know?
瑞典人的治疗师来干什么呢
What's the Swede's therapist doing here?
芬奇  我们得查清楚
Finch, we need to find out
为什么大家都对那瑞典人感兴趣
why everyone's so interested in the Swede.
海登的病人是个古董商
So Hayden's patient is an antiques dealer,
他花了一百万买张棒球卡
and he spent a million dollars on a baseball card?
捕捉图像
然后就当垃圾一样随手扔柜子里了
And then tossed it into some cabinet like it was junk.
图像搜索
发现匹配
我亲眼所见
I watched him do it.
太奇怪了
It's all very strange.
古董商的生意怎么会
And what business does an antique dealer have
跟HR的洗钱扯上关系呢
laundering HR's money in the first place?
为什么现在要他死呢
And why do they want him dead now?
看来瑞典人并没有找到真正的治疗师
Turns out the Swede wasn't going to a real therapist.
他全透给了一个骗子
He was spilling his guts to a con man.
那就来一个买一送一
We'll do a two for one special
把治疗师一起解决
and take out the therapist also.
我喜欢
I love that.
这晚餐是个大惊喜
You know, that dinner was such a surprise.
我非常开心
I had a lovely time.
那不是唯一的惊喜
That's not the only surprise.
我们出发吧  娜塔莉
Let's do it, Nat.
我们旅行
Let's take our trip.
去机场  选个目的地
Just go to the airport and pick our destination.
跟我走吗
Come with me?
海登  你是认真的吗
Hayd, are you serious?
那我们的工作  生活怎么办
What about our-- our jobs, our lives?
我们回来之后  一切照样
They'll be here for us when we get back.
我想冲动一次
I wanna be impulsive.
我想和心爱的姑娘浪迹天涯
I wanna whisk away the girl I love.
好  当然好
Yes. Of course.
什么时候动身
When do we leave?
这是另一个惊喜
That's the other surprise.
现在  不  明天
Now. No, tomorrow.
我还有些事情要做
I need to do a few things.
明天早上去接你
Pick you up in the A.M.?
我会火速打包
I'll pack fast.
芬奇  那骗子马上要出国了
Finch, our con man's blowing the country fast.
一定有事
Something's up.
上帝啊
Oh, my God.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait, wait.
你们是什么人
Who the hell are you?
守夜人
The night watch.
他们是什么人
Who were these guys?
警察  真警察
The cops-- the real cops.
到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
我们正打算问你呢  海登
We were gonna ask you the same thing, Hayden.
我刚和卡特警探通了电话
I just spoke with Detective Carter.
她认出你给我的警徽号码是HR的人
She identified the badge numbers you gave me as HR.
很确定
She's positive.
怎么回事  骗子
What's the deal, con man?
刚刚有人把我的办公室搅了个天翻地覆
Look. Someone just turned my office into Swiss cheese,
我女朋友还在等我
and my girlfriend is waiting for me.
如果她去我家  或者我办公室
If she goes back to my place or to my office--
我半小时前和娜塔莉联系过
I just spoke to Natalie a half an hour ago.
我告诉她  我是你的新助手
I explained to her how I was your new assistant
安排她去旅馆藏起来  等你去找她
and I needed to stash her in a motel until you'd visit her.
小小的谎言
Slight lie.
跟你的截然不同  海登
But nothing on a par with you, Hayden.
这话出自你口真有意思  冉先生
That's funny coming from you, Mr. Wren.
我们知道你一直在骗你的病人
We know you've been scamming your patients,
也知道你特别关注梵格先生
and we know you've had your eye especially on a Mr. Vanger,
那名古董商
the antique dealer.
你知道他为HR洗钱吗
Did you know he was a money launderer for HR?
我听说过HR  但我发誓
I've heard of HR, but I swear,
我不知道是他们的钱
I didn't know the money was theirs.
那你觉得你在骗谁的钱
Who'd you think you were grifting?
斯凡几个月前来找我
Sven came into my office a couple of months ago.
他是个烟鬼  账户里有几百万
He was a chain smoker who had millions bouncing around in his accounts.
本该很容易得手
It would have been an easy score.
结果你瞧
Look what happened.
我可没打算遇着真枪实弹
I didn't sign up for real bullets.
我不干这单了  我要离开这里
I'm done with this con and I'm out of here.
娜塔莉在哪儿
Where's Natalie?
想得美  哪儿都别去
Nice try. You're staying put.
我不是说了我不干这单了吗
What don't you get about "done"?
你们想让我出城
Look. You want me out of town?
我就出城
I'm out of town.
但我不会扔下她
But I can't go without her.
她是我生命中  唯一的真诚
See, she's the only honest thing left about me.
我必须紧紧抓住
I have to try and hold on to that.
警探  你发现
Detective, have you found out
古董商和HR洗钱的联系了吗
how the antique dealer is connected to HR's money laundering?
正在找路子
I'm meeting my source now.
你一口酒都没尝  乔丝
You haven't touched your wine, Joss.
-你下班了  -我从来不下班
- You're off duty. - I'm always on duty.
你听到我说的了吗
Have you heard a word I said?
洗钱这事儿你怎么看
What do you think about the money being laundered?
我听得清清楚楚
I heard every word.
那笔钱是HR从俄罗斯人那里敲来的
And the money's just HR's skim off the Russians.
其中一部分会给你那些制服朋友
A percentage kicked back to your friends in blue
买他们对约格洛夫的生意睁只眼闭只眼
for turning a blind eye to the Yogorov business.
请品尝一下蒙达奇诺布鲁尼洛干红
Please, try the Brunello di Montalcino.
余味非常美妙
The finish is quite exquisite.
我不明白的是
What I don't understand
HR从一个古董商手里能得到什么
is what HR wants with an antique business.
干净的钱
Clean money.
你看  HR不想要俄罗斯人血淋淋的脏钱
See, HR doesn't want blood-soaked bills from the Russians.
他们要把到手的钱化整为零
They want their cut in ones and zeroes,
转入他们的退休金账户
to transfer into their 401ks,
离岸账户
offshore accounts.
于是  古董商先把
So, the antique dealer cycles
俄罗斯人的黑钱放入自己的账户
the dirty Russian money into his own accounts
等待指令
and waits for instructions.
然后他去拍卖行
Then he heads to the auction house,
有人会指定他拍下某件高价拍品
where he's told to bid on a certain high-priced item,
而该拍品的出售人  正是HR的代表
an item auctioned off by a seller representing HR.
下一个拍品  编号426
Our next item up for bid is lot number 426--
绝世稀品棒球
an extremely rare baseball
上有1927年纽约洋基队全体的签名
signed by all of the 1927 New York Yankees,
包括卢・格里克和贝比・鲁斯
including Lou Gehrig and Babe Ruth.
号称"杀阵之球"
Informally named, "Murderer's Row Ball."
此物品起价
I'd like to start the bidding
200万
at $2 million.
有人出价200万
I got a bid for $2 million.
440万  哪里
$4.4 million. Where?
前边这位440万一次  两次
4.4 in the front going once, twice.
成交  440万  谢谢
Sold right here, $4.4 million. Thank you.
瑞典人出价最高  这样所有的黑钱
The Swede bids the highest, and all of that dirty money
就都转到HR名下了
is deposited into HR's coffers,
干净利落地洗白了
Squeaky clean and laundered,
随时可以转账
and ready for digital distribution.
但我不明白
But I don't get it.
这没有洗钱啊
They haven't laundered the money.
他们只买了个超贵的棒球
They've just bought an overpriced baseball.
所有HR的拍品
All the items HR auctions off
虽拍价高达上百万
may have been appraised for millions of dollars,
其实都是假货  赝品  不值钱的垃圾
but they're really just fugazis, fakes, worthless junk.
所以HR就白拿了俄罗斯人的钱
So HR gets Russian money for nothing?
这系统天衣无缝
It's a perfect system,
除非外边有人窥破天机
till someone on the outside knows about it.
要是那骗子以为自己能插手
So if your con man thinks he can just swoop in
分HR的一杯羹
and take a piece of HR's business,
他就得小心点了
He better watch his back.
你总是过来见谁啊
Who do you always meet in there?
不关你事
None of your business.
卡特  我一直在想
Carter, I've been thinking.
那个古董商
That antique dealer,
我不能就这么杀人
I can't just kill someone.
我当初进HR时  我没想
When I got involved with HR, I didn't think--
没想  你是没想
No, you didn't think.
你就睁只眼闭只眼
You just looked the other way.
我不能再那样了
I can't do that anymore.
现在只有你跟我同路了
And you're the only person I've got on my side right now.
我不跟你同路
I'm not on your side.
但我也不能眼睁睁看着命案发生
But I'm also not letting a homicide happen under my watch.
明天  你给我请病假
So, tomorrow, you're calling in sick.
我
I am?
是  给你个新任务
Yeah, see you just got a new job.
明天  给我跟踪西蒙斯
Tomorrow, you're Simmons's shadow.
他去哪  你就去哪
Wherever he goes, you go.
不管见谁  你都要拍照
Whoever he meets with, you get pictures of.
我刚发现他们的储钱罐
See, we just tapped into their piggy bank.
我想知道谁在掌管
Now I wanna know who's running the bank.
怎么回事
What is going on?
你去哪了
Where have you been?
那个  吓人的家伙是谁
What-- who is that creepy guy?
娜塔莉  对不起
Natalie, I'm so sorry.
你办公室有人给我打电话
I get a call from someone at your office
要我去什么酒店
telling me to come to some hotel,
你根本没露面
and then you don't even show up.
没事的  深呼吸
It's okay. You need to take a breath.
随着呼吸  慢慢平静
The more you breathe, the calmer you'll be.
不不不  不许催眠我
No, no, no. Do not hypno-talk me.
我没催眠你
I'm not hypno-talking you.
我是说  平静
I'm saying, just be calm--
我不是你的病人
I'm not one of your patients.
我知道  我知道
I know that, I know that.
你得告诉我
You have to tell me--
芬奇  你觉不觉得我们的工作
Finch, you ever notice how much of our job
像当保姆
is like babysitting?
这次可不止如此
It's more than that today.
海登似乎没把骗局对我们和盘托出
I don't think Hayden's told us the whole story of his con.
我在查看海登的硬盘
I'm going over Hayden's hard drive,
我在他销毁前下载的
what I downloaded of it before he zapped it.
我发现了古董商斯凡・梵格的邮箱
And I'm finding emails addressed to Sven Vanger, the antique dealer.
海登有可能
Hayden may have elicited
给他催眠时套出了邮箱密码
his email password while he was under hypnosis.
看来海登复制的这封邮件
It appears that Hayden duplicated an email
斯凡虽收到了  却还没读
that Sven had received, but not yet read.
他修改了内容
And he altered it in the process.
邮件什么内容
And what did the email say?
邮件来自匿名地址
The email is from an anonymous address,
提起今天有一场拍卖会
regarding an auction that took place today.
里边要求梵格去竞拍424号拍品
In it, Vanger was instructed to bid on lot 424,
但是海登修改了
But Hayden redrafted it,
要他去拍426号
instructing him to bid on lot 426.
也许该去问问海登为什么
Perhaps you should ask Hayden why.
他跳窗户出去了
He went out the window.
芬奇  海登利用他女朋友
Finch, Hayden used his girlfriend
偷偷溜走了
and gave us all the slip.
对不起  我要打烊了
I'm sorry. I'm about to close.
不  斯凡  你已经打烊了
No, Sven, you're already closed.
你哪边的  俄罗斯人的还是警察的
Who are you with, the Russians or the police?
我没东西给你
I have nothing left for you.
两边都不是
I'm not with either.
我来是要个东西  答案
But I do need something-- answers.
我不会任人宰割
I'm not your doormat.
放下枪别伤了自己吧  斯凡
Why don't you drop that before you hurt yourself, Sven?
交给我
Give it to me.
怎么最近你一打电话
Why is it every time you call me these days,
我就知道得带枪呢
I know to bring a firearm?
他是个好治疗师
But he was such a good therapist.
龙纹男
Dragon tattoo,
他还是个把你的钱全偷走的骗子
he's also a con man who stole from you.
不是我的钱  是他们的钱
Not stealing from me, stealing from them.
他真不该那么做
He should not be doing that.
你是怎么搅进这趟浑水的
How'd you even get into this mess?
七个月前  纽约海关要找我麻烦
Seven months ago, I got in trouble with the customs here in New York.
一名叫西蒙斯的警察来找我
A cop named Simmons came
说他可以摆平那些指控
and said he could make the charges go away
只要我帮他们的俄罗斯合伙人洗钱
if I helped them launder cash for a few Russian associates of theirs.
一开始  每月也就是几十万
At first, it was just a few hundred thousand each month.
之后数目越来越大  几百万了
Then it became more and more-- millions.
我今天刚甩掉最后一笔
I got rid of the last cash today.
426号拍品
On Lot 426?
你怎么知道的
How did you know about that?
海登耍了你
Hayden played you.
他篡改了你的电子邮件
He switched out your emails,
让你今天拍错了东西
and made you bid on the wrong item today.
那我买的是什么
Then what did I purchase?
真棒球
A real ball,
签有1927年洋基队真迹
signed by the real 1927 Yankees,
真正价值440万美元
really worth 4.4 million.
那年头儿是真牛
That was a hell of a season.
球在哪儿  斯凡
Where's the ball, Sven?
没了
It's gone.
我卖掉了  就五美元
I sold it for $5.
他们会干掉我的
They're going to kill me.
我得赶快跑路
I gotta get out of this city immediately!
太晚了  你已经被盯上了
Too late. You're a marked man.
把眼睛闭上  这玩意辣眼睛
Close your eyes. This stuff burns.
现在都开始伪造犯罪现场了
So we're faking crime scenes now?
跟在第八分局时真有差距啊
A long way from your days back at the Eighth.
得往边上撒点
Might wanna spread it out.
动脉出血喷得比较分散
Arterial spray is more erratic.
让我干活儿成不
Will you let me work?
要伪装成一种独特的中弹效果
Going for a kind of a hollow-point special kind of motif.
-好了  -恭喜
- There. - Congratulations.
你刚刚死而复生了
You've just died and been reborn.
现在  珍惜生命  滚出纽约
Now, take your new life, and get the hell out of New York.
短信
来自卡特
告诉西蒙斯你搞定瑞典人了
来电
西蒙斯
喂
Yeah?
菜鸟
Rookie,
你先别干掉那古董商
I need you to hold off on the antique dealer.
拍卖行那里出了点问题
Something went wrong at the auction house.
我们没拿到钱
We didn't get our money.
长官  有点小问题
Sir, there's a small problem.
我在HR的线人刚传来消息
Just heard from my source in HR,
西蒙斯知道他们上当了
Simmons knows they get ripped off.
要说棒球的事儿
All this baseball stuff,
你应该早点来找我的
you should've called me in sooner.
虽然我是大都会队的粉
I'm kind of a Mets fan, though.
洋基队和大都会队两支同为纽约棒球队
在城市的某个角落  某个小屁孩的兜里
Somewhere in the city, your soda kid's walking around
正装着那颗价值连城的棒球
with a zillion-dollar baseball in his pocket.
HR正在找那个球
With HR looking for the ball.
那小孩却对此一无所知
And the young man has no idea.
希望他别拿来练接球
Let's hope he don't play catch.
小子  有我的东西吗
Kiddo, you got something for me?
我真不敢相信海登会利用自己的女友
I can't believe Hayden would use his own girlfriend
借机逃跑
as an excuse to escape.
我相信  价值四百万的棒球
I can. A baseball worth 4 million
吸引力可不小
would be a motivational force.
他也不在乎自己逃走
He doesn't care who he steps on
会连累多少人
to get away with it either.
正是  他仍要逃走
Exactly. He still has to get away,
但他不会扔下娜塔莉
but he won't go without Natalie.
你我都非常清楚
As you and I well know,
理性与感性常常相互冲突
sometimes necessity and desire can conflict.
海登还在城里
Hayden's still in the city.
他不会蠢到用自己的手机
He's too smart to use his own phone.
那我们怎么追踪他
So how do we track him?
不用管他  我们追踪娜塔莉
We don't. We track Natalie.
海登正在给她打电话
Hayden's calling her right now.
娜  拜托  我很抱歉
Nat, please, I'm sorry.
我确实做过不应该的事
I've done things that I'm not proud of,
但我爱你
but I love you.
相信我好吗
Can you trust me on that?
我想知道现在到底是怎么回事
I wanna know what's going on right now.
情况有点复杂  娜
That's a little complicated, Nat.
-等等  你在哪儿  -回家
- Wait. Where are you? - I'm going home.
你以为你跳窗户出去之后
Did you think I was just gonna sit in that hotel room
我还会待在那酒店房间里吗
after you went out the window?
不  亲爱的  你不能回去
No, honey, you can't go there.
那里不安全
It's not safe for you.
真的吗  我怎么会知道呢
Really? How would I even know?
听着  海登  我爱你
Look, Hayden, I love you.
但我得知道真相  否则算了
But I deserve the truth, or else I'm done.
我是罪犯  是贼
I'm a criminal and a thief.
但我不再干了
But I'm done with that life.
我赚了一笔钱可以确保我们的未来
I secured a score that will ensure our future.
数额巨大  足以让我们随便挑选目的地
The kind of score that would let us pick our destination.
只要一小时后在我旧办公室外见面
If you meet me outside my old office in one hour,
我们就可以按计划飞往世界的任一角落
then we can fly to any corner of the world, like we planned.
然后我会对你和盘托出
And I'll tell you everything.
你可以不再爱我  甚至恨我
Stop loving me or even hate me,
但请先听我解释
but please hear me out.
我会过去
I'll be there.
我不想让你烦心
I didn't wanna worry you.
我在收拾这烂摊子了
I'm cleanin' up this mess.
你说是瑞典人买了那个棒球
You say the Swede bought the baseball?
拍卖行的记录上是这么写的
That's what the logs at the auction house said.
但没他
But without him,
要找到球有点困难
it's gonna be a little tough to track it.
那个白痴买了一颗有真迹的棒球
That idiot bought a real autographed ball
价值440万美元
worth $4.4 million,
而那个菜鸟在我们
and we had a rookie kill him
发现真相之前就杀了他
before we found out what he did with it?
也许该让那个菜鸟来帮你善后
Maybe the rookie should be handling your end of things.
至少他能完成任务
At least he follows through.
你刚说有个骗子参与其中
But you said there was a con man involved.
-是的  -找到他
- Yeah. - Find him.
逼他把那该死的球找出来
Shake him till the damn ball falls out.
告诉我你至少有一条线索
And tell me you have at least one lead.
我们窃听他电话时
When we tapped his phone,
找出了骗子的小女朋友
we found out about the con man's little girlfriend.
他似乎深陷爱河
It seems the guy's in love.
他不会扔下她走人
He ain't going anywhere without her.
给我搞定  西蒙斯
Make it right, Simmons.
我有两个真爱  我的钱和这座城市
I got two loves-- my money and this city.
敢碰这两样的  我会报复
Mess with either, I mess right back.
小白脸
Lover boy.
能怎么样  我就是骗子
What'd you expect? I'm a crook.
他是我的专家
He's my expert.
怎么  你不相信我
What, you don't trust me?
如你所说  你是骗子
Like you said, you're a crook.
我可不是啥专家  不过看起来挺真
I don't know about expert, but it looks pretty damn real.
我有买家在等着了
I have a buyer lined up.
我们平分  五五
I'll split it with you, 50/50.
-六四  -这买卖不错啊
- 60/40? - Not a half bad deal, huh?
你们至少容我打个电话给娜塔莉
Will you at least let me call Natalie
再宰了我  或逮捕我
before you kill me or arrest me
或把我关到地下室吧
or put me in a well in your basement?
给你30秒
You have 30 seconds.
抱歉让你失望了  骗子
Sorry to disappoint, con man.
看来纽约警局的电话追踪技术不错
Seems the NYPD isn't bad at phone traces.
我20分钟内就找到你女友了
I found your girl in 20 minutes.
我把棒球给你  是你的了
I'll give you the ball. It's yours.
别装高尚  咱们都是罪犯
Don't be noble. There's only criminals on this line.
不过棒球我还是要的
But I'll take the ball, just the same.
20分钟后在拍卖行门前见
You meet me in front of the auction house in 20 minutes.
情况多糟
How bad is it?
他们会杀死她
They'll kill her.
那些人  为了这么一大笔钱
These people, for this much money?
那你打算怎么阻止他们
So what are you gonna do to stop them?
我是个人渣  我明白
I'm scum. I get it.
可娜塔莉
But Natalie--
我的终极骗局  最后一笔是为了
My ultimate con, my final trick was gonna be
真正变成她深爱的那个人
actually turning into the guy that she fell in love with.
我什么都可以放弃  只要能救她
I'll give it all away to save her life.
你会帮我吗
Will you help me?
这么安排
This is how it goes.
菜鸟带着女孩待在外面
Rookie stays outside with the girl.
铁尼  把骗子带进屋
Terney, take the con man inside,
验证球的真假
verify the ball is real.
对这个小丑我不能再冒险了
I'm not taking any more chances with this clown.
为什么要我进去
Why do I have to go inside?
因为我说的
Because that's what you were just told.
一旦我们确认球是真的
Once we confirm the ball is the real deal,
拉斯基抓着那姑娘  给她头上两枪
Laskey takes the girl, puts a double tap in her head.
有问题吗
Questions?
老大  她一无所知
Boss, uh, she doesn't know anything.
何不放她走
Why don't we just let her go?
我今天看起来像要接受菜鸟的意见吗
Do I look like I'm taking suggestions from rookies today?
不  长官
No, sir.
球呢
The ball?
我女友呢
The girl.
我要和娜塔莉说话
I wanna talk to Natalie.
你得先进去
You're going inside first.
我只相信  一日为贼  终身为贼
One thing you can trust about a thief is he'll always be a thief.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
钱和尸体搞定后给我电话
Call me when there's money and bodies.
拉斯基
Laskey.
你说对了  卡特
You were right, Carter.
他们不会放她走
They would never let her go.
弄得逼真点
Make it look good.
记住  目的不是伤他
Remember, the aim shouldn't be to hurt him,
打晕就行
just incapacitate him a little.
还有  小心指关节
Also, watch your knuckles.
我揍过很多人
I've punched a lot of guys.
我也是
So have I.
带你去个安全的地方
Let's get you to safety.
我们已经彻底检查了一遍  是真的
We've been through this already, it's real.
要不是真的你觉得我会站在这里吗
You think I'd be standing here if it wasn't?
等着瞧吧
We'll see.
一分钟内就知道了
I'll know in a minute.
我需要用显微镜确定一下
I need a microscope to know for sure,
不过纹理是对的
but the texture appears accurate.
但是  有个问题
There is, however, a problem.
什么
What?
看到这个了吗  巴比・鲁斯的签名
See this? Babe Ruth's signature?
看到了  怎么了
Yeah. What about it?
是用毡尖笔写的
It's in felt-tip pen.
巴比・鲁斯在世的时候还没这种笔
Those didn't exist when Babe Ruth was alive.
这球是赝品
This ball is a fake.
你给我们赝品  你给我们赝品
You give us a fake? You give us a fake?
你想死吗
You wanna die?
我发誓  那是真的
I swear, that is the real ball.
真球值400万美元
The real ball costs $4 million.
赝品值你一颗子弹  骗子
The fake is just gonna cost you a bullet, con man.
我为什么要说谎
Why would I lie?
你得相信我
You have to believe me.
我们能解决的
We can figure this out.
真球在哪儿
Where is the real ball?
铁尼
Terney.
那真球在哪儿
So where's the real ball?
我不知道
I have no idea.
我以为这球是真的
I thought this was the real ball.
不管了  娜塔莉呢
Forget that. Where's Natalie?
我帮她打的  让她去安全的地方
I put her in a cab, told her to go somewhere safe.
我是娜塔莉
This is Natalie.
娜  你在哪
Nat, where are you?
你还好吧
Are you okay?
我好得不得了
I'm better than okay.
那古董商
You see, that antique dealer--
他的名字是斯凡
Sven was his name well,
他虽然是你的大目标
he may have been your big score,
但打从一开始  你就是我钓的大鱼
but you were my big whale, from the moment I met you.
你  你玩我
You--you played me?
何必从罪犯那儿偷几百万呢
Why steal millions from criminals
不如跟贼交往  顺手牵羊呢
when you can date the thief and take it off him?
不用找了
Keep the change.
当然  那些腐败警察搞得有些麻烦
Of course, things did get a little hairy with those corrupt cops,
但你总知道如何哄女人开心  海登
but you always did know how to show a girl a good time, Hayden.
你要去哪里
Where will you go?
找个机场
Go find an airport,
随便找个目的地
maybe just pick a destination.
岂不是美梦成真吗
Isn't that the dream come true?
你知道  我真的爱过你
You know, I really did love you.
既然是真爱  那就放手吧
If you love something, set it free.
我完了
I'm ruined.
也许你该循规蹈矩过日子了
Maybe it's time you went on the straight and narrow.
会活久一点
You'll live longer.
我听说近来催眠治疗师的市场需求很大
I hear hypnotherapists are in pretty high demand these days.
我确实可以重整旗鼓
You know, I do have a thriving practice to rebuild.
我得找个新办公室  没弹孔的
I'm gonna need a new office with a few less bullet holes.
我的建议
My advice?
去别的城市重整吧
Rebuild in another city.
铁尼警探  我注意到你没把球带来
Detective Terney, I can't help but notice you're not carrying a ball.
那骗子带来的球是假的
The ball the con man brought was a fake.
那西装男出现了  放倒了拉斯基和我们
The guy with the suit showed up, rolled Laskey and our guys,
然后跟那骗子和他女朋友跑了
and then got away with the con man and his girl.
你知道现在最紧要的是什么吗
Do you have any idea what's at stake here?
去找那坏事的拉斯基
You go find that screw-up Laskey
翻遍全城也要找到那个球
and you scour this city until you find that ball.
西蒙斯  我不是菜鸟
Simmons, I'm not the rookie.
别这样跟我说话
Don't talk to me like one.
你找不到那个球
If you don't find that ball,
你们俩的葬礼可就值四百万美元了
then it's gonna be a $4 million funeral for the both of you.
快去
Now go.
我刚把夜灯关掉了
I was just turning out the lights for the evening,
格罗夫斯女士  我记得
Ms. Groves, and I remembered that
我答应要给你送点新书过来
I had promised to bring you some new reading material.
示好礼物吗  哈罗德
A peace offering, Harold?
你就是带这个来了吗
Is that what you've brought?
我真的认为  如果你从我的角度来理解
I really think if you could just see things my way,
而不是把这当成
and not consider this--
监禁
Imprisonment?
这还能理解成什么
Is there any other way to consider it?
这真是为你好  格罗夫斯女士
This truly is for your own good, Ms. Groves.
我是真心的
I mean that when I say it.
那种
This
你和机器之间的同步联系
synchronistic relationship that you've developed with the machine,
不能
it can't be--
我担心你
I worry about you.
你错估了形势
You've misunderstood the situation.
你不该担心我
You shouldn't worry about me.
我担心你  哈罗德
I'm worried about you, Harold.
你不能阻止未来  我也不能
You can't stop what's coming, and neither can I.
但我们有机会
But we have the opportunity
在事成定局前  去了解
to understand things when they finally change.
未来就要到来
The future is coming.
你开启
You started it...
我完成
and I'll finish it.
我现在不在  请留言
You missed me. Leave a message.
拉斯基  我在你家外头
Laskey, I'm outside your place.
我们有很多事要做  快来
We have a lot of work to do. Come on.
我紧紧跟着那家伙
I stuck to the guy like glue.
西蒙斯见的人都在这儿了
This is everyone Simmons met with.
谢了  孩子  你做得不错
Thanks, kid, you did all right.
但你要知道  情况会越来越严重
But you should know, it'll get harder out there.
经过这几天的事儿  事态会升级
After these last few days, things are gonna heat up.
你得做好准备
So you need to be prepared.
我加入HR时
When I got involved with HR,
自以为它代表忠诚
I thought it was about loyalty.
我错了
I was wrong.
其实它只有谋杀和贪婪
It's about murder and greed.
勾结上了啊
Ain't that cozy.
我早该知道她会策反你  菜鸟
I should've known she'd turn you, rookie.
第一次见你  我就知道你软弱
The first time I saw you, I knew you were weak.
让我告诉你个真实的世界吧  孩子
So let me tell you how the world works now, kid.
要么我们杀了她  要么他们杀了我们
We kill her or they kill us.
那将是你的最后决定  铁尼
That decision is gonna be your last, Terney.
不
No!
拉斯基
Laskey?
流这么多血
That much blood,
你只能撑一分钟了  最多两分钟
and you'll be dead in a minute, maybe two.
死得有价值点
Make 'em count.
你和西蒙斯向谁汇报
Who do you and Simmons report to?
谁发号施令
Who calls the shots?
答案在这些照片里吗
Is the answer in these pictures, huh?
最后机会了  铁尼  拿出警察样来
Last chance, Terney! Be a cop!